María Alejandra Pérez UX / UI Designer

mapb1989@gmail.com 677709274 Barcelona, Spain

linkedin.com/in/mapb1989 mariaalejandraperez.com

UX / UI Designer with a background in engineering. My experience has taught me how to communicate with stakeholders, provide timely solutions for support incidences, and design processes that understand the customer's struggles and motivations. All of these lessons have inspired me and have made me focused on UX design.

PROJECTS

UX / UI Project at Ironhack

Stream Pals: app for SVOD services recommendations

- UX Research, IA, Interaction design, UI Design.
- Goal: Offer accurate recommendations for movies and shows streaming services.

UX / UI Project at Ironhack

FixVid: an E-learning app for home repairs

- UX Research, IA, Interaction design.
- Goal: Helping people perform house repairs while saving time and gaining independence.

EDUCATION

UX / UI Designer

Ironhack 12/2019 - 06/2020

Barcelona, Spain

Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya 09/2014 – 02/2017

Barcelona, Spain

Electronic Engineer

Universidad Simón Bolívar 09/2007 – 12/2012

Caracas, Venezuela

LANGUAGES

| Spanish | | | | |
|---------|---|---|---|---|
| English | | | | |
| German | | 0 | 0 | 0 |
| Catalan | 0 | 0 | 0 | 0 |

SKILLS

Technologies & tools

Figma | Sketch | Invision | Marvel | HTML5 | CSS | Jira | Git | Zeplin

Soft skills

Problem solving | Adaptability | Coordination | Time management | Empathy

Hard skills

Prototyping | Design thinking | UX Research | UI Design | Interaction Design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Social & Beyond (Barcelona, Spain)

Software provider of Smart WiFi and proximity marketing

Lead Customer Support Engineer (05/2018 – 04/2020)

- Manage support team and helping clients with any issues regarding the performance and configuration of their access point and routers.
- Analyze, improve and maintain the company's operational processes.
- Homologation, troubleshooting and testing of hardware.
- Write technical documents related to the company products.
- Report, replicate and track bugs in the production environment.

Support and Presales Engineer (04/2016 – 05/2018)

- Analyze and design WiFi networks according to project requirements.
- Manage customers' project from contract signature to end of installation.
- Provide training and support to customers as required.